[{"num":1,"sample":"1A11","correct":"A","question":"What is a requirement of all marine transmitting apparatus used aboard United States vessels? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOnly equipment that has been certified by the FCC for Part 80 operations is authorized. ","b":"B.\tEquipment must be type-accepted by the U.S. Coast Guard for maritime mobile use. ","c":"C.\tCertification is required by the International Maritime Organization (IMO). ","d":"D.\tProgramming of all maritime channels must be performed by a licensed Marine Radio Operator"}},{"num":2,"sample":"1A12","correct":"B","question":"What transmitting equipment is authorized for use by a station in the maritime services? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTransmitters that have been certified by the manufacturer for maritime use. ","b":"B.\tUnless specifically excepted, only transmitters certified by the Federal Communications Commission for Part 80 operations. ","c":"C.\tEquipment that has been inspected and approved by the U.S. Coast Guard. ","d":"D.\tTransceivers and transmitters that meet all ITU specifications for use in maritime mobile service"}},{"num":3,"sample":"1A13","correct":"D","question":"Small passenger vessels that sail 20 to 150 nautical miles from the nearest land must have what additional equipment? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tInmarsat-B terminal. ","b":"B.\tInmarsat-C terminal. ","c":"C.\tAircraft Transceiver with 121.5 MHz. ","d":"D.\tMF-HF SSB Transceiver"}},{"num":4,"sample":"1A14","correct":"C","question":"What equipment is programmed to initiate transmission of distress alerts and calls to individual stations? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tNAVTEX. ","b":"B.\tGPS. ","c":"C.\tDSC controller. ","d":"D.\tScanning Watch Receiver"}},{"num":5,"sample":"1A15","correct":"B","question":"What is the minimum transmitter power level required by the FCC for a medium-frequency transmitter aboard a compulsorily fitted vessel? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAt least 100 watts, single-sideband, suppressed-carrier power. ","b":"B.\tAt least 60 watts PEP. ","c":"C.\tThe power predictably needed to communicate with the nearest public coast station operating on 2182 kHz. ","d":"D.\tAt least 25 watts delivered into 50 ohms effective resistance when operated with a primary voltage of 13.6 volts DC"}},{"num":6,"sample":"1A16","correct":"D","question":"Shipboard transmitters using F3E emission (FM voice) may not exceed what carrier power? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t500 watts. ","b":"B.\t250 watts. ","c":"C.\t100 watts. ","d":"D.\t25 watts"}},{"num":7,"sample":"1A21","correct":"D","question":"Which commercial radio operator license is required to operate a fixed-tuned ship RADAR station with external controls? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA radio operator certificate containing a Ship RADAR Endorsement. ","b":"B.\tA Marine Radio Operator Permit or higher. ","c":"C.\tEither a First or Second Class Radiotelegraph certificate or a General Radiotelephone Operator License. ","d":"D.\tNo radio operator authorization is required"}},{"num":8,"sample":"1A22","correct":"C","question":"When is a Marine Radio Operator Permit or higher license required for aircraft communications? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tWhen operating on frequencies below 30 MHz allocated exclusively to aeronautical mobile services. ","b":"B.\tWhen operating on frequencies above 30 MHz allocated exclusively to aeronautical mobile services. ","c":"C.\tWhen operating on frequencies below 30 MHz not allocated exclusively to aeronautical mobile services. ","d":"D.\tWhen operating on frequencies above 30 MHz not assigned for international use"}},{"num":9,"sample":"1A23","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following persons are ineligible to be issued a commercial radio operator license? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIndividuals who are unable to send and receive correctly by telephone spoken messages in English. ","b":"B.\tHandicapped persons with uncorrected disabilities which affect their ability to perform all duties required of commercial radio operators. ","c":"C.\tForeign maritime radio operators unless they are certified by the International Maritime Organization (IMO). ","d":"D.\tU.S"}},{"num":10,"sample":"1A24","correct":"D","question":"What are the radio operator requirements of a passenger ship equipped with a GMDSS installation? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe operator must hold a General Radiotelephone Operator License or higher-class license. ","b":"B.\tThe operator must hold a Restricted Radiotelephone Operator Permit or higher-class license. ","c":"C.\tThe operator must hold a Marine Radio Operator Permit or higher-class license. ","d":"D.\tTwo operators on board must hold a GMDSS Radio Operator License or a Restricted GMDSS Radio Operator License, depending on the ship's operating areas"}},{"num":11,"sample":"1A25","correct":"C","question":"What is the minimum radio operator requirement for ships subject to the Great Lakes Radio Agreement? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThird Class Radiotelegraph Operator's Certificate. ","b":"B.\tGeneral Radiotelephone Operator License. ","c":"C.\tMarine Radio Operator Permit. ","d":"D.\tRestricted Radiotelephone Operator Permit"}},{"num":12,"sample":"1A26","correct":"B","question":"What is a requirement of every commercial operator on duty and in charge of a transmitting system? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA copy of the Proof-of-Passing Certificate (PPC) must be in the station's records. ","b":"B.\tThe original license or a photocopy must be posted or in the operator's personal possession and available for inspection. ","c":"C.\tThe FCC Form 605 certifying the operator's qualifications must be readily available at the transmitting system site. ","d":"D.\tA copy of the operator's license must be supplied to the radio station's supervisor as evidence of technical qualification"}},{"num":13,"sample":"1A31","correct":"C","question":"Radio watches for compulsory radiotelephone stations will include the following: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tVHF channel 22a continuous watch at sea. ","b":"B.\t121.5 MHz continuous watch at sea. ","c":"C.\tVHF channel 16 continuous watch. ","d":"D.\t500 kHz"}},{"num":14,"sample":"1A32","correct":"A","question":"All compulsory equipped cargo ships (except those operating under GMDSS regulations or in a VTS) while being navigated outside of a harbor or port, shall keep a continuous radiotelephone watch on: ","answers":{"a":"A.\t2182 kHz and Ch-16. ","b":"B.\t2182 kHz. ","c":"C.\tCh-16. ","d":"D.\tCargo ships are exempt from radio watch regulations"}},{"num":15,"sample":"1A33","correct":"D","question":"What channel must all compulsory, non-GMDSS vessels monitor at all times in the open sea? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tChannel 8. ","b":"B.\tChannel 70. ","c":"C.\tChannel 6. ","d":"D.\tChannel 16"}},{"num":16,"sample":"1A34","correct":"A","question":"When a watch is required on 2182 kHz, at how many minutes past the hour must a 3 minute silent period be observed? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t00, 30. ","b":"B.\t15, 45. ","c":"C.\t10, 40. ","d":"D.\t05, 35"}},{"num":17,"sample":"1A35","correct":"D","question":"Which is true concerning a required watch on VHF Ch-16? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt is compulsory at all times while at sea until further notice, unless the vessel is in a VTS system. ","b":"B.\tWhen a vessel is in an A1 sea area and subject to the Bridge-to-Bridge act and in a VTS system, a watch is not required on Ch-16, provided the vessel monitors both Ch-13 and VTS channel. ","c":"C.\tIt is always compulsory in sea areas A2, A3 and A4. ","d":"D.\tAll of the above"}},{"num":18,"sample":"1A36","correct":"B","question":"What are the mandatory DSC watchkeeping bands/channels? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tVHF Ch-70, 2 MHz MF DSC, 6 MHz DSC and 1 other HF DSC. ","b":"B.\t8 MHz HF DSC, 1 other HF DSC, 2 MHz MF DSC and VHF Ch-70. ","c":"C.\t2 MHz MF DSC, 8 MHz DSC, VHF Ch-16 and 1 other HF DSC. ","d":"D.\tNone of the above"}},{"num":19,"sample":"1A41","correct":"B","question":"Who is required to make entries in a required service or maintenance log? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe licensed operator or a person whom he or she designates. ","b":"B.\tThe operator responsible for the station operation or maintenance. ","c":"C.\tAny commercial radio operator holding at least a Restricted Radiotelephone Operator Permit. ","d":"D.\tThe technician who actually makes the adjustments to the equipment"}},{"num":20,"sample":"1A42","correct":"D","question":"Who is responsible for the proper maintenance of station logs? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe station licensee. ","b":"B.\tThe commercially-licensed radio operator in charge of the station. ","c":"C.\tThe ship's master and the station licensee. ","d":"D.\tThe station licensee and the radio operator in charge of the station"}},{"num":21,"sample":"1A43","correct":"A","question":"Where must ship station logs be kept during a voyage? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAt the principal radiotelephone operating position. ","b":"B.\tThey must be secured in the vessel's strongbox for safekeeping. ","c":"C.\tIn the personal custody of the licensed commercial radio operator. ","d":"D.\tAll logs are turned over to the ship's master when the radio operator goes off duty"}},{"num":22,"sample":"1A44","correct":"C","question":"What is the proper procedure for making a correction in the station log? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe ship's master must be notified, approve and initial all changes to the station log. ","b":"B.\tThe mistake may be erased and the correction made and initialized only by the radio operator making the original error. ","c":"C.\tThe original person making the entry must strike out the error, initial the correction and indicate the date of the correction. ","d":"D.\tRewrite the new entry in its entirety directly below the incorrect notation and initial the change"}},{"num":23,"sample":"1A45","correct":"B","question":"How long should station logs be retained when there are entries relating to distress or disaster situations? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tUntil authorized by the Commission in writing to destroy them. ","b":"B.\tFor a period of three years from the last date of entry, unless notified by the FCC. ","c":"C.\tIndefinitely, or until destruction is specifically authorized by the U.S. Coast Guard. ","d":"D.\tFor a period of one year from the last date of entry"}},{"num":24,"sample":"1A46","correct":"C","question":"How long should station logs be retained when there are no entries relating to distress or disaster situations? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tFor a period of three years from the last date of entry, unless notified by the FCC. ","b":"B.\tUntil authorized by the Commission in writing to destroy them. ","c":"C.\tFor a period of two years from the last date of entry. ","d":"D.\tIndefinitely, or until destruction is specifically authorized by the U.S"}},{"num":25,"sample":"1A51","correct":"D","question":"Radiotelephone stations required to keep logs of their transmissions must include: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tStation, date and time. ","b":"B.\tName of operator on duty. ","c":"C.\tStation call signs with which communication took place. ","d":"D.\tAll of these"}},{"num":26,"sample":"1A52","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following is true? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBattery test must be logged daily. ","b":"B.\tEPIRB tests are normally logged monthly. ","c":"C.\tRadiotelephone tests are normally logged weekly. ","d":"D.\tNone of the above"}},{"num":27,"sample":"1A53","correct":"C","question":"Where should the GMDSS radio log be kept on board ship? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCaptain's office. ","b":"B.\tSea cabin. ","c":"C.\tAt the GMDSS operating position. ","d":"D.\tAnywhere on board the vessel"}},{"num":28,"sample":"1A54","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following statements is true? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tKey letters or abbreviations may be used in GMDSS Radio Logbooks if their meaning is noted in the log. ","b":"B.\tKey letters or abbreviations may not be used in GMDSS Radio Logbooks under any circumstances. ","c":"C.\tAll Urgency communications must be entered in the logbook. ","d":"D.\tNone of the above"}},{"num":29,"sample":"1A55","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following logkeeping statements is true? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tEntries relating to pre-voyage, pre-departure and daily tests are required. ","b":"B.\tBoth a) and c) ","c":"C.\tA summary of all required Distress communications heard and Urgency communications affecting the station's own ship.  Also, all Safety communications (other than VHF) affecting the station's own ship must be logged. ","d":"D.\tRoutine daily MF-HF and Inmarsat-C transmissions do not have to be logged"}},{"num":30,"sample":"1A56","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following statements concerning log entries is false? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAll Safety communications received on VHF must be logged. ","b":"B.\tAll required equipment tests must be logged. ","c":"C.\tThe radio operator must log on and off watch. ","d":"D.\tThe vessels daily position must be entered in the log"}},{"num":31,"sample":"1A61","correct":"B","question":"What regulations govern the use and operation of FCC-licensed ship stations in international waters? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe regulations of the International Maritime Organization (IMO) and Radio Officers Union. ","b":"B.\tPart 80 of the FCC Rules plus the international Radio Regulations and agreements to which the United States is a party. ","c":"C.\tThe Maritime Mobile Directives of the International Telecommunication Union. ","d":"D.\tThose of the FCC's Wireless Telecommunications Bureau, Maritime Mobile Service, Washington, DC 20554"}},{"num":32,"sample":"1A62","correct":"C","question":"When may the operator of a ship radio station allow an unlicensed person to speak over the transmitter? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAt no time.  Only commercially-licensed radio operators may modulate the transmitting apparatus. ","b":"B.\tWhen the station power does not exceed 200 watts peak envelope power. ","c":"C.\tWhen under the supervision of the licensed operator. ","d":"D.\tDuring the hours that the radio officer is normally off duty"}},{"num":33,"sample":"1A63","correct":"C","question":"Where do you make an application for inspection of a ship GMDSS radio station? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTo a Commercial Operator Licensing Examination Manager (COLE Manager). ","b":"B.\tTo the Federal Communications Commission, Washington, DC 20554. ","c":"C.\tTo the Engineer-in-Charge of the FCC District Office nearest the proposed place of inspection. ","d":"D.\tTo an FCC-licensed technician holding a GMDSS Radio Maintainer's License"}},{"num":34,"sample":"1A64","correct":"A","question":"Who has ultimate control of service at a ship's radio station? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe master of the ship. ","b":"B.\tA holder of a First Class Radiotelegraph Certificate with a six months' service endorsement. ","c":"C.\tThe Radio Officer-in-Charge authorized by the captain of the vessel. ","d":"D.\tAn appointed licensed radio operator who agrees to comply with all Radio Regulations in force"}},{"num":35,"sample":"1A65","correct":"C","question":"Where must the principal radiotelephone operating position be installed in a ship station? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAt the principal radio operating position of the vessel. ","b":"B.\tIn the chart room, master's quarters or wheel house. ","c":"C.\tIn the room or an adjoining room from which the ship is normally steered while at sea. ","d":"D.\tAt the level of the main wheel house or at least one deck above the ship's main deck"}},{"num":36,"sample":"1A66","correct":"D","question":"By international agreement, which ships must carry radio equipment for the safety of life at sea? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAll ships traveling more than 100 miles out to sea. ","b":"B.\tCargo ships of more than 100 gross tons and passenger vessels on international deep-sea voyages. ","c":"C.\tAll cargo ships of more than 100 gross tons. ","d":"D.\tCargo ships of more than 300 gross tons and vessels carrying more than 12 passengers"}},{"num":37,"sample":"1B71","correct":"B","question":"What traffic management service is operated by the U.S. Coast Guard in certain designated water areas to prevent ship collisions, groundings and environmental harm? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tWater Safety Management Bureau (WSMB). ","b":"B.\tVessel Traffic Service (VTS). ","c":"C.\tShip Movement and Safety Agency (SMSA). ","d":"D.\tInterdepartmental Harbor and Port Patrol (IHPP)"}},{"num":38,"sample":"1B72","correct":"D","question":"What is a bridge-to-bridge station? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAn internal communications system linking the wheel house with the ship's primary radio operating position and other integral ship control points. ","b":"B.\tAn inland waterways and coastal radio station serving ship stations operating within the United States. ","c":"C.\tA portable ship station necessary to eliminate frequent application to operate a ship station on board different vessels. ","d":"D.\tA VHF radio station located on a ship's navigational bridge or main control station that is used only for navigational communications"}},{"num":39,"sample":"1B73","correct":"A","question":"When may a bridge-to-bridge transmission be more than 1 watt? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tWhen broadcasting a distress message and rounding a bend in a river or traveling in a blind spot. ","b":"B.\tWhen broadcasting a distress message. ","c":"C.\tWhen rounding a bend in a river or traveling in a blind spot. ","d":"D.\tWhen calling the Coast Guard"}},{"num":40,"sample":"1B74","correct":"D","question":"When is it legal to transmit high power on Channel 13? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tFailure of vessel being called to respond. ","b":"B.\tIn a blind situation such as rounding a bend in a river. ","c":"C.\tDuring an emergency. ","d":"D.\tAll of these"}},{"num":41,"sample":"1B75","correct":"A","question":"A ship station using VHF bridge-to-bridge Channel 13: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMay be identified by the name of the ship in lieu of call sign. ","b":"B.\tMay be identified by call sign and country of origin. ","c":"C.\tMust be identified by call sign and name of vessel. ","d":"D.\tDoes not need to identify itself within 100 miles from shore"}},{"num":42,"sample":"1B76","correct":"C","question":"The primary purpose of bridge-to-bridge communications is: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSearch and rescue emergency calls only. ","b":"B.\tAll short-range transmission aboard ship. ","c":"C.\tNavigational communications. ","d":"D.\tTransmission of Captain's orders from the bridge"}},{"num":43,"sample":"1B81","correct":"C","question":"What is the best way for a radio operator to minimize or prevent interference to other stations? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBy using an omni-directional antenna pointed away from other stations. ","b":"B.\tReducing power to a level that will not affect other on-frequency communications. ","c":"C.\tDetermine that a frequency is not in use by monitoring the frequency before transmitting. ","d":"D.\tBy changing frequency when notified that a radiocommunication causes interference"}},{"num":44,"sample":"1B82","correct":"B","question":"Under what circumstances may a coast station using telephony transmit a general call to a group of vessels? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tUnder no circumstances. ","b":"B.\tWhen announcing or preceding the transmission of Distress, Urgency, Safety or other important messages. ","c":"C.\tWhen the vessels are located in international waters beyond 12 miles. ","d":"D.\tWhen identical traffic is destined for multiple mobile stations within range"}},{"num":45,"sample":"1B83","correct":"C","question":"Who determines when a ship station may transmit routine traffic destined for a coast or government station in the maritime mobile service? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tShipboard radio officers may transmit traffic when it will not interfere with ongoing radiocommunications. ","b":"B.\tThe order and time of transmission and permissible type of message traffic is decided by the licensed on-duty operator. ","c":"C.\tShip stations must comply with instructions given by the coast or government station. ","d":"D.\tThe precedence of conventional radiocommunications is determined by FCC and international regulation"}},{"num":46,"sample":"1B84","correct":"A","question":"What is required of a ship station which has established initial contact with another station on 2182 kHz or Ch-16? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe stations must change to an authorized working frequency for the transmission of messages. ","b":"B.\tThe stations must check the radio channel for Distress, Urgency and Safety calls at least once every ten minutes. ","c":"C.\tRadiated power must be minimized so as not to interfere with other stations needing to use the channel. ","d":"D.\tTo expedite safety communications, the vessels must observe radio silence for two out of every fifteen minutes"}},{"num":47,"sample":"1B85","correct":"D","question":"How does a coast station notify a ship that it has a message for the ship? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBy making a directed transmission on 2182 kHz or 156.800 MHz. ","b":"B.\tThe coast station changes to the vessel's known working frequency. ","c":"C.\tBy establishing communications using the eight-digit maritime mobile service identification. ","d":"D.\tThe coast station may transmit, at intervals, lists of call signs in alphabetical order for which they have traffic"}},{"num":48,"sample":"1B86","correct":"B","question":"What is the priority of communications? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSafety, Distress, Urgency and radio direction-finding. ","b":"B.\tDistress, Urgency and Safety. ","c":"C.\tDistress, Safety, radio direction-finding, search and rescue. ","d":"D.\tRadio direction-finding, Distress and Safety"}},{"num":49,"sample":"1B91","correct":"A","question":"Under what circumstances may a ship or aircraft station interfere with a public coast station? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIn cases of distress. ","b":"B.\tUnder no circumstances during on-going radiocommunications. ","c":"C.\tDuring periods of government priority traffic handling. ","d":"D.\tWhen it is necessary to transmit a message concerning the safety of navigation or important meteorological warnings"}},{"num":50,"sample":"1B92","correct":"B","question":"Ordinarily, how often would a station using a telephony emission identify? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAt least every 10 minutes. ","b":"B.\tAt the beginning and end of each transmission and at 15-minute intervals. ","c":"C.\tAt 15-minute intervals, unless public correspondence is in progress. ","d":"D.\tAt 20-minute intervals"}},{"num":51,"sample":"1B93","correct":"D","question":"When using a SSB station on 2182 kHz or VHF-FM on channel 16: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tPreliminary call must not exceed 30 seconds. ","b":"B.\tIf contact is not made, you must wait at least 2 minutes before repeating the call. ","c":"C.\tOnce contact is established, you must switch to a working frequency. ","d":"D.\tAll of these"}},{"num":52,"sample":"1B94","correct":"A","question":"What should a station operator do before making a transmission? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tExcept for the transmission of distress calls, determine that the frequency is not in use by monitoring the frequency before transmitting. ","b":"B.\tTransmit a general notification that the operator wishes to utilize the channel. ","c":"C.\tCheck transmitting equipment to be certain it is properly calibrated. ","d":"D.\tAsk if the frequency is in use"}},{"num":53,"sample":"1B95","correct":"B","question":"On what frequency should a ship station normally call a coast station when using a radiotelephony emission? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOn a vacant radio channel determined by the licensed radio officer. ","b":"B.\tCalls should be initiated on the appropriate ship-to-shore working frequency of the coast station. ","c":"C.\tOn any calling frequency internationally approved for use within ITU Region 2. ","d":"D.\tOn 2182 kHz or Ch-16 at any time"}},{"num":54,"sample":"1B96","correct":"C","question":"In the International Phonetic Alphabet, the letters E, M, and S are represented by the words: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tEcho, Michigan, Sonar. ","b":"B.\tEquator, Mike, Sonar. ","c":"C.\tEcho, Mike, Sierra. ","d":"D.\tElement, Mister, Scooter"}},{"num":55,"sample":"1B101","correct":"D","question":"What information must be included in a Distress message? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tName of vessel. ","b":"B.\tLocation. ","c":"C.\tType of distress and specifics of help requested. ","d":"D.\tAll of the above"}},{"num":56,"sample":"1B102","correct":"C","question":"What are the highest priority communications from ships at sea? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAll critical message traffic authorized by the ship's master. ","b":"B.\tNavigation and meteorological warnings. ","c":"C.\tDistress calls are highest and then communications preceded by Urgency and then Safety signals. ","d":"D.\tAuthorized government communications for which priority right has been claimed"}},{"num":57,"sample":"1B103","correct":"B","question":"What is a Distress communication? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCommunications indicating that the calling station has a very urgent message concerning safety. ","b":"B.\tAn internationally recognized communication indicating that the sender is threatened by grave and imminent danger and requests immediate assistance. ","c":"C.\tRadio communications which, if delayed, will adversely affect the safety of life or property. ","d":"D.\tAn official radio communication notification of approaching navigational or meteorological hazards"}},{"num":58,"sample":"1B104","correct":"C","question":"What is the order of priority of radiotelephone communications in the maritime services? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAlarm and health and welfare communications. ","b":"B.\tNavigation hazards, meteorological warnings, priority traffic. ","c":"C.\tDistress calls and signals, followed by communications preceded by Urgency and Safety signals and all other communications. ","d":"D.\tGovernment precedence, messages concerning safety of life and protection of property, and traffic concerning grave and imminent danger"}},{"num":59,"sample":"1B105","correct":"D","question":"The radiotelephone Distress call and message consists of: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMAYDAY spoken three times, followed by the name of the vessel and the call sign in phonetics spoken three times. ","b":"B.\tParticulars of its position, latitude and longitude, and other information which might facilitate rescue, such as length, color and type of vessel, and number of persons on board. ","c":"C.\tNature of distress and kind of assistance required. ","d":"D.\tAll of the above"}},{"num":60,"sample":"1B106","correct":"A","question":"What is Distress traffic? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAll messages relative to the immediate assistance required by a ship, aircraft or other vehicle threatened by grave or imminent danger, such as life and safety of persons on board, or man overboard. ","b":"B.\tIn radiotelephony, the speaking of the word, 'Mayday.' ","c":"C.\tHealth and welfare messages concerning property and the safety of a vessel. ","d":"D.\tInternationally recognized communications relating to important situations"}},{"num":61,"sample":"1B111","correct":"A","question":"What is a typical Urgency transmission? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA request for medical assistance that does not rise to the level of a Distress or a critical weather transmission higher than Safety. ","b":"B.\tA radio Distress transmission affecting the security of humans or property. ","c":"C.\tHealth and welfare traffic which impacts the protection of on-board personnel. ","d":"D.\tA communications alert that important personal messages must be transmitted"}},{"num":62,"sample":"1B112","correct":"B","question":"What is the internationally recognized Urgency signal? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe letters 'TTT' transmitted three times by radiotelegraphy. ","b":"B.\tThe words 'PAN PAN' spoken three times before the Urgency call. ","c":"C.\tThree oral repetitions of the word 'Safety' sent before the call. ","d":"D.\tThe pronouncement of the word 'Mayday'"}},{"num":63,"sample":"1B113","correct":"A","question":"What is a Safety transmission? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA communications transmission which indicates that a station is preparing to transmit an important navigation or weather warning. ","b":"B.\tA radiotelephony warning preceded by the words 'PAN PAN.' ","c":"C.\tHealth and welfare traffic concerning the protection of human life. ","d":"D.\tA voice call proceeded by the words 'Safety Alert'"}},{"num":64,"sample":"1B114","correct":"C","question":"The Urgency signal concerning the safety of a ship, aircraft or person shall be sent only on the authority of: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMaster of ship. ","b":"B.\tPerson responsible for mobile station. ","c":"C.\tEither Master of ship or person responsible for mobile station. ","d":"D.\tAn FCC-licensed operator"}},{"num":65,"sample":"1B115","correct":"B","question":"The Urgency signal has lower priority than: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tShip-to-ship routine calls. ","b":"B.\tDistress. ","c":"C.\tSafety. ","d":"D.\tSecurity"}},{"num":66,"sample":"1B116","correct":"D","question":"What safety signal call word is spoken three times, followed by the station call letters spoken three times, to announce a storm warning, danger to navigation, or special aid to navigation? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tPAN PAN. ","b":"B.\tMAYDAY. ","c":"C.\tSAFETY. ","d":"D.\tSECURITE"}},{"num":67,"sample":"1B121","correct":"D","question":"What is the fundamental concept of the GMDSS? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt is intended to automate and improve existing digital selective calling procedures and techniques. ","b":"B.\tIt is intended to provide more effective but lower cost commercial communications. ","c":"C.\tIt is intended to provide compulsory vessels with a collision avoidance system when they are operating in waters that are also occupied by non-compulsory vessels. ","d":"D.\tIt is intended to automate and improve emergency communications in the maritime industry"}},{"num":68,"sample":"1B122","correct":"C","question":"The primary purpose of the GMDSS is to: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAllow more effective control of SAR situations by vessels. ","b":"B.\tProvide additional shipboard systems for more effective company communications. ","c":"C.\tAutomate and improve emergency communications for the world's shipping industry. ","d":"D.\tProvide effective and inexpensive communications"}},{"num":69,"sample":"1B123","correct":"D","question":"What is the basic concept of GMDSS? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tShoreside authorities and vessels can assist in a coordinated SAR operation with minimum delay. ","b":"B.\tSearch and rescue authorities ashore can be alerted to a Distress situation. ","c":"C.\tShipping in the immediate vicinity of a ship in Distress will be rapidly alerted. ","d":"D.\tAll of these"}},{"num":70,"sample":"1B124","correct":"D","question":"GMDSS is primarily a system based on? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tShip-to-ship Distress communications using MF or HF radiotelephony. ","b":"B.\tVHF digital selective calling from ship to shore. ","c":"C.\tDistress, Urgency and Safety communications carried out by the use of narrow-band direct printing telegraphy. ","d":"D.\tThe linking of search and rescue authorities ashore with shipping in the immediate vicinity of a ship in Distress or in need of assistance"}},{"num":71,"sample":"1B125","correct":"C","question":"What is the responsibility of vessels under GMDSS? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tVessels over 300 gross tons may be required to render assistance if such assistance does not adversely affect their port schedule. ","b":"B.\tOnly that vessel, regardless of size, closest to a vessel in Distress, is required to render assistance. ","c":"C.\tEvery ship is able to perform those communications functions that are essential for the Safety of the ship itself and of other ships. ","d":"D.\tVessels operating under GMDSS, outside of areas effectively serviced by shoreside authorities, operating in sea areas A2, and A4 may be required to render assistance in Distress situations"}},{"num":72,"sample":"1B126","correct":"B","question":"GMDSS is required for which of the following? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAll vessels capable of international voyages. ","b":"B.\tSOLAS Convention ships of 300 gross tonnage or more. ","c":"C.\tVessels operating outside of the range of VHF coastal radio stations. ","d":"D.\tCoastal vessels of less than 300 gross tons"}},{"num":73,"sample":"1C131","correct":"C","question":"What is the purpose of the INT-USA control settings on a VHF? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTo change all VTS frequencies to Duplex so all vessels can receive maneuvering orders. ","b":"B.\tTo change all VHF channels from Duplex to Simplex while in U.S. waters. ","c":"C.\tTo change certain International Duplex channel assignments to simplex in the U.S. for VTS and other purposes. ","d":"D.\tTo change to NOAA weather channels and receive weather broadcasts while in the U.S"}},{"num":74,"sample":"1C132","correct":"A","question":"VHF ship station transmitters must have the capability of reducing carrier power to: ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1 watt. ","b":"B.\t10 watts. ","c":"C.\t25 watts. ","d":"D.\t50 watts"}},{"num":75,"sample":"1C133","correct":"D","question":"The Dual Watch (DW) function is used to: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tListen to Ch-70 at the same time while monitoring Ch-16. ","b":"B.\tSequentially monitor 4 different channels. ","c":"C.\tSequentially monitoring all VHF channels. ","d":"D.\tListen on any selected channel while periodically monitoring Ch-16"}},{"num":76,"sample":"1C134","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following statements best describes the correct setting for manual adjustment of the squelch control? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAdjust squelch control to the minimum level necessary to barely suppress any background noise. ","b":"B.\tAlways adjust squelch control to its maximum level. ","c":"C.\tAlways adjust squelch control to its minimum level. ","d":"D.\tAdjust squelch control to approximately twice the minimum level necessary to barely suppress any background noise"}},{"num":77,"sample":"1C135","correct":"D","question":"The 'Scan' function is used to: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMonitor  Ch-16 continuously and switching to either Ch-70 or Ch-13 every 5 seconds. ","b":"B.\tScan Ch-16 for Distress calls. ","c":"C.\tScan Ch-70 for Distress alerts. ","d":"D.\tSequentially scan all or selected channels"}},{"num":78,"sample":"1C136","correct":"B","question":"Why must all VHF Distress, Urgency and Safety communications (as well as VTS traffic calls) be performed in Simplex operating mode? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTo minimize interference from vessels engaged in routine communications. ","b":"B.\tTo ensure that vessels not directly participating in the communications can hear both sides of the radio exchange. ","c":"C.\tTo enable an RCC or Coast station to only hear communications from the vessel actually in distress. ","d":"D.\tTo allow an RCC or Coast station to determine which transmissions are from other vessels and which transmissions are from the vessel actually in distress"}},{"num":79,"sample":"1C141","correct":"B","question":"What channel must VHF-FM-equipped vessels monitor at all times when the vessel is at sea? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tChannel 8. ","b":"B.\tChannel 16. ","c":"C.\tChannel 5A. ","d":"D.\tChannel 1A"}},{"num":80,"sample":"1C142","correct":"D","question":"What is the aircraft frequency and emission used for distress communications? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t243.000 MHz - F3E. ","b":"B.\t121.500 MHz - F3E. ","c":"C.\t156.525 MHz - F1B. ","d":"D.\t121.500 MHz - A3E"}},{"num":81,"sample":"1C143","correct":"A","question":"Which VHF channel is used only for digital selective calling? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tChannel 70. ","b":"B.\tChannel 16. ","c":"C.\tChannel 22A. ","d":"D.\tChannel 6"}},{"num":82,"sample":"1C144","correct":"C","question":"Which channel is utilized for the required bridge-to-bridge watch? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDSC on Ch-70. ","b":"B.\tVHF-FM on Ch-16. ","c":"C.\tVHF-FM on Ch-13 in most areas of the continental United States. ","d":"D.\tThe vessel's VHF working frequency"}},{"num":83,"sample":"1C145","correct":"B","question":"Which channel would most likely be used for routine ship-to-ship voice traffic? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCh-16. ","b":"B.\tCh-08. ","c":"C.\tCh-70. ","d":"D.\tCh-22A"}},{"num":84,"sample":"1C146","correct":"C","question":"What channel would you use to place a call to a shore telephone? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCh-16. ","b":"B.\tCh-70. ","c":"C.\tCh-28. ","d":"D.\tCh-06"}},{"num":85,"sample":"1C151","correct":"D","question":"Which modes could be selected to receive vessel traffic lists from high seas shore stations? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAM and VHF-FM. ","b":"B.\tARQ and FEC. ","c":"C.\tVHF-FM and SSB. ","d":"D.\tSSB and FEC"}},{"num":86,"sample":"1C152","correct":"B","question":"Why must all MF-HF Distress, Urgency and Safety communications take place solely on the 6 assigned frequencies and in the simplex operating mode? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tFor non-GMDSS ships, to maximize the chances for other vessels to receive those communications. ","b":"B.\tAnswers a) and c) are both correct. ","c":"C.\tFor GMDSS or DSC-equipped ships, to maximize the chances for other vessels to receive those communications following the transmission of a DSC call of the correct priority. ","d":"D.\tTo enable an RCC or Coast station to only hear communications from the vessel actually in distress"}},{"num":87,"sample":"1C153","correct":"C","question":"To set-up the MF/HF transceiver for a voice call to a coast station, the operator must: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSelect J3E mode for proper SITOR operations. ","b":"B.\tSelect F1B mode or J2B mode, depending on the equipment manufacturer. ","c":"C.\tSelect J3E mode for proper voice operations. ","d":"D.\tSelect F1B/J2B modes or J3E mode, depending on whether FEC or ARQ is preferred"}},{"num":88,"sample":"1C154","correct":"A","question":"MF/HF transceiver power levels should be set: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTo the lowest level necessary for effective communications. ","b":"B.\tTo the level necessary to maximize the propagation radius. ","c":"C.\tTo the highest level possible so as to ensure other stations cannot 'break-in' on the channel during use. ","d":"D.\tBoth a) and c) are correct"}},{"num":89,"sample":"1C155","correct":"B","question":"To set-up the MF/HF transceiver for a TELEX call to a coast station, the operator must: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSelect J3E mode for proper SITOR operations. ","b":"B.\tSelect F1B mode or J2B mode, depending on the equipment manufacturer. ","c":"C.\tSelect F1B/J2B modes or J3E mode, depending on whether ARQ or FEC is preferred. ","d":"D.\tNone of the above"}},{"num":90,"sample":"1C156","correct":"A","question":"What is the purpose of the Receiver Incremental Tuning (RIT) or 'Clarifier' control? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt acts as a 'fine-tune' control on the receive frequency. ","b":"B.\tIt acts as a 'fine-tune' control on the transmitted frequency. ","c":"C.\tIt acts as a 'fine-tune' control on both the receive and transmitted frequencies. ","d":"D.\tNone of the above"}},{"num":91,"sample":"1C161","correct":"B","question":"On what frequency would a vessel normally call another ship station when using a radiotelephony emission? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOnly on 2182 kHz in ITU Region 2. ","b":"B.\tOn 2182 kHz or Ch-16, unless the station knows that the called vessel maintains a simultaneous watch on another intership working frequency. ","c":"C.\tOn the appropriate calling channel of the ship station at 15 minutes past the hour. ","d":"D.\tOn the vessel's unique working radio channel assigned by the Federal Communications Commission"}},{"num":92,"sample":"1C162","correct":"C","question":"What is the MF radiotelephony calling and Distress frequency? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t2670 kHz. ","b":"B.\tCh-06 VHF. ","c":"C.\t2182 kHz. ","d":"D.\tCh-22 VHF"}},{"num":93,"sample":"1C163","correct":"D","question":"For general communications purposes, paired frequencies are: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tNormally used with private coast stations. ","b":"B.\tNormally used between ship stations. ","c":"C.\tNormally used between private coast and ship stations. ","d":"D.\tNormally used with public coast stations"}},{"num":94,"sample":"1C164","correct":"A","question":"What emission must be used when operating on the MF distress and calling voice frequency? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tJ3E - Single sideband telephony. ","b":"B.\tA1A - On-off keying without modulation by an audio frequency. ","c":"C.\tF3E - Frequency modulation telephony. ","d":"D.\tA3E - Amplitude modulation telephony, double sideband"}},{"num":95,"sample":"1C165","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following defines high frequency 'ITU Channel 1212'? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCh-12 in the 16 MHz band. ","b":"B.\tCh-1216 in the MF band. ","c":"C.\tThe 12th channel in the 12 MHz band. ","d":"D.\tThis would indicate the 1st channel in the 12 MHz band"}},{"num":96,"sample":"1C166","correct":"D","question":"For general communications purposes, simplex frequencies are: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tNormally used between ship stations and private coast stations. ","b":"B.\tNormally used with public coast stations. ","c":"C.\tNormally used between ship stations. ","d":"D.\tBoth a) and c) are correct"}},{"num":97,"sample":"1C171","correct":"B","question":"What is the proper procedure for testing a radiotelephone installation? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA dummy antenna must be used to insure the test will not interfere with ongoing communications. ","b":"B.\tTransmit the station's call sign, followed by the word 'test' on the frequency being used for the test. ","c":"C.\tPermission for the voice test must be requested and received from the nearest public coast station. ","d":"D.\tShort tests must be confined to a single frequency and must never be conducted in port"}},{"num":98,"sample":"1C172","correct":"D","question":"When testing is conducted on 2182 kHz or Ch-16, testing should not continue for more than ______ in any 5-minute period. ","answers":{"a":"A.\t2 minutes. ","b":"B.\t1 minute. ","c":"C.\t30 seconds. ","d":"D.\t10 seconds"}},{"num":99,"sample":"1C173","correct":"A","question":"Under GMDSS, a compulsory VHF-DSC radiotelephone installation must be tested at what minimum intervals at sea? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDaily. ","b":"B.\tAnnually, by a representative of the FCC. ","c":"C.\tWeekly. ","d":"D.\tMonthly"}},{"num":100,"sample":"1C174","correct":"D","question":"The best way to test the MF-HF NBDP system is? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMake a radiotelephone call to a coast station. ","b":"B.\tInitiate an ARQ call to demonstrate that the transmitter and antenna are working. ","c":"C.\tInitiate an FEC call to demonstrate that the transmitter and antenna are working. ","d":"D.\tInitiate an ARQ call to a Coast Station and wait for the automatic exchange of answerbacks"}},{"num":101,"sample":"1C175","correct":"A","question":"The best way to test the Inmarsat-C terminal is? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCompose and send a brief message to your own Inmarsat-C terminal. ","b":"B.\tSend a message to a shore terminal and wait for confirmation. ","c":"C.\tSend a message to another ship terminal. ","d":"D.\tIf the 'Send' light flashes, proper operation has been confirmed"}},{"num":102,"sample":"1C176","correct":"C","question":"When may you test a radiotelephone transmitter on the air? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBetween midnight and 6:00 AM local time. ","b":"B.\tOnly when authorized by the Commission. ","c":"C.\tAt any time (except during silent periods) as necessary to assure proper operation. ","d":"D.\tAfter reducing transmitter power to 1 watt"}},{"num":103,"sample":"1C181","correct":"C","question":"Under normal circumstances, what do you do if the transmitter aboard your ship is operating off-frequency, overmodulating or distorting? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tReduce to low power. ","b":"B.\tReduce audio volume level. ","c":"C.\tStop transmitting. ","d":"D.\tMake a notation in station operating log"}},{"num":104,"sample":"1C182","correct":"B","question":"Which would be an indication of proper operation of a SSB transmitter rated at 60 watt PEP output? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIn SSB (J3E) voice mode, with the transmitter keyed but without speaking into the microphone, power output is indicated. ","b":"B.\tIn SITOR communications, the power meter can be seen fluctuating regularly from zero to the 60 watt relative output reading. ","c":"C.\tIn SSB (J3E) mode, speaking into the microphone causes power meter to fluctuate slightly around the 60 watt reading. ","d":"D.\tA steady indication of transmitted energy on an RF Power meter with no fluctuations when speaking into the microphone"}},{"num":105,"sample":"1C183","correct":"C","question":"If a ship radio transmitter signal becomes distorted: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tReduce transmitter power. ","b":"B.\tUse minimum modulation. ","c":"C.\tCease operations. ","d":"D.\tReduce audio amplitude"}},{"num":106,"sample":"1C184","correct":"A","question":"What would be an indication of a malfunction on a GMDSS station with a 24 VDC battery system? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA constant 30 volt reading on the GMDSS console voltmeter. ","b":"B.\tAfter testing the station on battery power, the ammeter reading indicates a high rate of charge that then declines. ","c":"C.\tAfter testing the station on battery power, a voltmeter reading of 30 volts for brief period followed by a steady 26 volt reading. ","d":"D.\tNone of the above"}},{"num":107,"sample":"1C185","correct":"D","question":"Your antenna tuner becomes totally inoperative. What would you do to obtain operation on both the 8 MHz and 22 MHz frequency bands? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tWithout an operating antenna tuner, transmission is impossible. ","b":"B.\tIt is impossible to obtain operation on 2 different HF bands, without an operating antenna tuner. ","c":"C.\tBypass the antenna tuner and shorten the whip to 15 ft. ","d":"D.\tBypass the antenna tuner"}},{"num":108,"sample":"1C186","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following conditions would be a symptom of malfunction in a 2182 kHz radiotelephone system that must be reported to the Master, then logged appropriately. ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMuch higher noise level observed during daytime operation. ","b":"B.\tNo indication of power output when speaking into the microphone. ","c":"C.\tWhen testing a radiotelephone alarm on 2182 kHz into an artificial antenna, the Distress frequency watch receiver becomes unmuted, an improper testing procedure. ","d":"D.\tFailure to contact a shore station 600 nautical miles distant during daytime operation"}},{"num":109,"sample":"1D191","correct":"A","question":"What are the antenna requirements of a VHF telephony coast, maritime utility or ship station? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe shore or on-board antenna must be vertically polarized. ","b":"B.\tThe antenna array must be type-accepted for 30-200 MHz operation by the FCC. ","c":"C.\tThe horizontally-polarized antenna must be positioned so as not to cause excessive interference to other stations. ","d":"D.\tThe antenna must be capable of being energized by an output in excess of 100 watts"}},{"num":110,"sample":"1D192","correct":"B","question":"What is the antenna requirement of a radiotelephone installation aboard a passenger vessel? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe antenna must be located a minimum of 15 meters from the radiotelegraph antenna. ","b":"B.\tThe antenna must be vertically polarized and as non-directional and efficient as is practicable for the transmission and reception of ground waves over seawater. ","c":"C.\tAn emergency reserve antenna system must be provided for communications on 156.800 MHz. ","d":"D.\tAll antennas must be tested and the operational results logged at least once during each voyage"}},{"num":111,"sample":"1D193","correct":"D","question":"What is the most common type of antenna for GMDSS VHF? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tHorizontally polarized circular antenna. ","b":"B.\tLong wire antenna. ","c":"C.\tBoth of the above. ","d":"D.\tNone of the above"}},{"num":112,"sample":"1D194","correct":"A","question":"What is the purpose of the antenna tuner? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt alters the electrical characteristics of the antenna to match the frequency in use. ","b":"B.\tIt physically alters the length of the antenna to match the frequency in use. ","c":"C.\tIt makes the antenna look like a half-wave antenna at the frequency in use. ","d":"D.\tNone of the above"}},{"num":113,"sample":"1D195","correct":"B","question":"What advantage does a vertical whip have over a long wire? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt radiates more signal fore and aft. ","b":"B.\tIt radiates equally well in all directions. ","c":"C.\tIt radiates a strong signal vertically. ","d":"D.\tNone of the above"}},{"num":114,"sample":"1D196","correct":"C","question":"A vertical whip antenna has a radiation pattern best described by? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA figure eight. ","b":"B.\tA cardioid. ","c":"C.\tA circle. ","d":"D.\tAn ellipse"}},{"num":115,"sample":"1D201","correct":"D","question":"For a small passenger vessel inspection, reserve power batteries must be tested: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAt intervals not exceeding every 3 months. ","b":"B.\tAt intervals not exceeding every 6 months ","c":"C.\tBefore any new voyage ","d":"D.\tAt intervals not exceeding 12 months, or during the inspection"}},{"num":116,"sample":"1D202","correct":"C","question":"What are the characteristics of the Reserve Source of Energy under GMDSS? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSupplies independent HF and MF installations at the same time. ","b":"B.\tCannot be independent of the propelling power of the ship. ","c":"C.\tMust be independent of the ship's electrical system when the RSE is needed to supply power to the GMDSS equipment. ","d":"D.\tMust be incorporated into the ship's electrical system"}},{"num":117,"sample":"1D203","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following terms is defined as a back-up power source that provides power to radio installations for the purpose of conducting Distress and Safety communications when the vessel's main and emergency generators cannot? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tEmergency Diesel Generator. ","b":"B.\tReserve Source of Energy. ","c":"C.\tReserve Source of Diesel Power. ","d":"D.\tEmergency Back-up Generator"}},{"num":118,"sample":"1D204","correct":"C","question":"In the event of failure of the main and emergency sources of electrical power, what is the term for the source required to supply the GMDSS console with power for conducting distress and other radio communications? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tEmergency power. ","b":"B.\tShip's emergency diesel generator. ","c":"C.\tReserve source of energy. ","d":"D.\tShip's standby generator"}},{"num":119,"sample":"1D205","correct":"D","question":"What is the requirement for emergency and reserve power in GMDSS radio installations? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAn emergency power source for radio communications is not required if a vessel has proper reserve power (batteries). ","b":"B.\tA reserve power source is not required for radio communications. ","c":"C.\tOnly one of the above is required if a vessel is equipped with a second 406 EPIRB as a backup means of sending a distress alert. ","d":"D.\tAll newly constructed ships under GMDSS must have both emergency and reserve power sources for radio communications"}},{"num":120,"sample":"1D206","correct":"A","question":"What is the meaning of 'Reserve Source of Energy'? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe supply of electrical energy sufficient to operate the radio installations for the purpose of conducting Distress and Safety communications in the event of failure of the ship's main and emergency sources of electrical power. ","b":"B.\tHigh caloric value items for lifeboat, per SOLAS regulations. ","c":"C.\tDiesel fuel stored for the purpose of operating the powered survival craft for a period equal to or exceeding the U.S.C.G. and SOLAS requirements. ","d":"D.\tNone of these"}},{"num":121,"sample":"1D211","correct":"A","question":"What is an EPIRB? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA battery-operated emergency position-indicating radio beacon that floats free of a sinking ship. ","b":"B.\tAn alerting device notifying mariners of imminent danger. ","c":"C.\tA satellite-based maritime distress and safety alerting system. ","d":"D.\tA high-efficiency audio amplifier"}},{"num":122,"sample":"1D212","correct":"B","question":"When are EPIRB batteries changed? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAfter emergency use; after battery life expires. ","b":"B.\tAfter emergency use or within the month and year replacement date printed on the EPIRB. ","c":"C.\tAfter emergency use; every 12 months when not used. ","d":"D.\tWhenever voltage drops to less than 20% of full charge"}},{"num":123,"sample":"1D213","correct":"A","question":"If a ship sinks, what device is designed to float free of the mother ship, is turned on automatically and transmits a distress signal? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAn emergency position indicating radio beacon. ","b":"B.\tEPIRB on 2182 kHz and 405.025 kHz. ","c":"C.\tBridge-to-bridge transmitter on 2182 kHz. ","d":"D.\tAuto alarm keyer on any frequency"}},{"num":124,"sample":"1D214","correct":"C","question":"How do you cancel a false EPIRB distress alert? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTransmit a DSC distress alert cancellation. ","b":"B.\tTransmit a broadcast message to 'all stations' canceling the distress message. ","c":"C.\tNotify the Coast Guard or rescue coordination center at once. ","d":"D.\tMake a radiotelephony 'distress cancellation' transmission on 2182 kHz"}},{"num":125,"sample":"1D215","correct":"B","question":"What is the COSPAS-SARSAT system? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA global satellite communications system for users in the maritime, land and aeronautical mobile services. ","b":"B.\tAn international satellite-based search and rescue system. ","c":"C.\tA broadband military satellite communications network. ","d":"D.\tA Wide Area Geostationary Satellite program (WAGS)"}},{"num":126,"sample":"1D216","correct":"D","question":"What is an advantage of a 406 MHz satellite EPIRB? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt is compatible with the COSPAS-SARSAT Satellites and Global Maritime Distress  Safety System (GMDSS) regulations. ","b":"B.\tProvides a fast, accurate method for  the Coast Guard to locating and rescuing persons in distress. ","c":"C.\tIncludes a digitally encoded message containing the ship's identity and nationality. ","d":"D.\tAll of the above"}},{"num":127,"sample":"1D221","correct":"D","question":"In which frequency band does a search and rescue transponder operate? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t3 GHz. ","b":"B.\tS-band. ","c":"C.\t406 MHz. ","d":"D.\t9 GHz"}},{"num":128,"sample":"1D222","correct":"C","question":"How should the signal from a Search And Rescue Radar Transponder appear on a RADAR display? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA series of dashes. ","b":"B.\tA series of spirals all originating from the range and bearing of the SART. ","c":"C.\tA series of 12 equally spaced dots. ","d":"D.\tA series of twenty dashes"}},{"num":129,"sample":"1D223","correct":"A","question":"What is the purpose of the SART's audible tone alarm? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt informs survivors that assistance may be nearby. ","b":"B.\tIt informs survivors when the battery's charge condition has weakened. ","c":"C.\tIt informs survivors when the SART switches to the 'standby' mode. ","d":"D.\tIt informs survivors that a nearby vessel is signaling on DSC"}},{"num":130,"sample":"1D224","correct":"D","question":"Which statement is true regarding the SART? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThis is a performance monitor attached to at least one S-band navigational RADAR system. ","b":"B.\tThis is a 9 GHz transponder capable of being received by another vessel's S-band navigational RADAR system. ","c":"C.\tThis is a performance monitor attached to at least one X-band navigational RADAR system. ","d":"D.\tThis is a 9 GHz transponder capable of being received by vessel's X-band navigational RADAR system"}},{"num":131,"sample":"1D225","correct":"C","question":"At what point does a SART begin transmitting? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt immediately begins radiating when placed in the 'on' position. ","b":"B.\tIt must be manually activated. ","c":"C.\tIf it has been placed in the 'on' position, it will respond when it has been interrogated by a 9-GHz RADAR signal. ","d":"D.\tIf it has been placed in the 'on' position, it will begin transmitting immediately upon detecting that it is in water"}},{"num":132,"sample":"1D226","correct":"B","question":"How can a SART's effective range be maximized? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe SART should be placed in water immediately upon activation. ","b":"B.\tThe SART should be held as high as possible. ","c":"C.\tSwitch the SART into the 'high' power position. ","d":"D.\tIf possible, the SART should be mounted horizontally so that its signal matches that of the searching RADAR signal"}},{"num":133,"sample":"1D231","correct":"C","question":"Which statement is NOT true regarding the requirements of survival craft portable two-way VHF radiotelephone equipment? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tWatertight to a depth of 1 meter for 5 minutes. ","b":"B.\tEffective radiated power should be a minimum of 0.25 watts. ","c":"C.\tOperates simplex on Ch-70 and at least one other channel. ","d":"D.\tThe antenna is fixed and non-removable"}},{"num":134,"sample":"1D232","correct":"A","question":"Which statement is NOT true regarding the requirements of survival craft portable two-way VHF radiotelephone equipment? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOperation on Ch-13. ","b":"B.\tEffective radiated power should be a minimum of 0.25 Watts. ","c":"C.\tSimplex voice communications only. ","d":"D.\tOperation on Ch-16"}},{"num":135,"sample":"1D233","correct":"D","question":"With what other stations may portable survival craft transceivers communicate? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCommunication is permitted between survival craft. ","b":"B.\tCommunication is permitted between survival craft and ship. ","c":"C.\tCommunication is permitted between survival craft and rescue unit. ","d":"D.\tAll of the above"}},{"num":136,"sample":"1D234","correct":"A","question":"Equipment for radiotelephony use in survival craft stations under GMDSS must have what capability? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOperation on Ch-16. ","b":"B.\tOperation on 457.525 MHz. ","c":"C.\tOperation on 121.5 MHz. ","d":"D.\tAny one of these"}},{"num":137,"sample":"1D235","correct":"D","question":"Equipment for radiotelephony use in survival craft stations under GMDSS must have what characteristic(s)? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOperation on Ch-16. ","b":"B.\tWatertight. ","c":"C.\tPermanently-affixed antenna. ","d":"D.\tAll of these"}},{"num":138,"sample":"1D236","correct":"B","question":"What is the minimum power of the SCT ","answers":{"a":"A.\tFive watts. ","b":"B.\tOne watt. ","c":"C.\t&frac14; watt. ","d":"D.\tNone of the above"}},{"num":139,"sample":"1D241","correct":"B","question":"NAVTEX broadcasts are sent: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tImmediately following traffic lists. ","b":"B.\tIn categories of messages indicated by a single letter or identifier. ","c":"C.\tOn request of maritime mobile stations. ","d":"D.\tRegularly, after the radiotelephone silent periods"}},{"num":140,"sample":"1D242","correct":"D","question":"MSI can be obtained by one (or more) of the following: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tNAVTEX. ","b":"B.\tSafetyNET. ","c":"C.\tHF NBDP. ","d":"D.\tAll of the above"}},{"num":141,"sample":"1D243","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following is the primary frequency that is used exclusively for NAVTEX broadcasts internationally? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t518 kHz. ","b":"B.\t2187.5 kHz. ","c":"C.\t4209.5 kHz. ","d":"D.\tVHF channel 16 when the vessel is sailing in Sea Area A1, and 2187.5 kHz when in Sea Area A2"}},{"num":142,"sample":"1D244","correct":"C","question":"What means are used to prevent the reception of unwanted broadcasts by vessels utilizing the NAVTEX system? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOperating the receiver only during daytime hours. ","b":"B.\tCoordinating reception with published broadcast schedules. ","c":"C.\tProgramming the receiver to reject unwanted broadcasts. ","d":"D.\tAutomatic receiver de-sensitization during night hours"}},{"num":143,"sample":"1D245","correct":"B","question":"When do NAVTEX broadcasts typically achieve maximum transmitting range? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tLocal noontime. ","b":"B.\tMiddle of the night. ","c":"C.\tSunset. ","d":"D.\tPost sunrise"}},{"num":144,"sample":"1D246","correct":"C","question":"What is the transmitting range of most NAVTEX stations? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTypically 50-100 nautical miles (90-180 km) from shore. ","b":"B.\tTypically upwards of 1000 nautical miles (1800 km) during the daytime. ","c":"C.\tTypically 200-400 nautical miles (360-720 km). ","d":"D.\tIt is limited to line-of-sight or about 30 nautical miles (54 km)"}}]
